It takes all sorts to make a world – so some say.
有人说，世界因多样而精彩。
Nobody is the same, and our different personalities and character traits make us what we are.
每个人都是独一无二的，我们不同的个性和性格特质造就了独特的自己。
Wouldn’t it be boring if we were all the same?
如果所有人都一模一样，那岂不是太无趣了？
But if someone doesn’t behave or think like you, it can be frustrating.
但如果有人的言行举止或思维方式与你截然不同，难免会让人感到沮丧。
And there’s one personality type that can be very difficult to deal with - narcissism.
而有一种人格类型尤其难以相处——那就是自恋型人格。
Narcissists consider themselves the most important person.
自恋者认为自己是最重要的人。
They’re only interested in their own life, without a care in the world about the people around them.
他们只关心自己的生活，对身边的人漠不关心。
Their lack of empathy makes them come across as arrogant and self-important.
缺乏同理心的特质让他们显得傲慢自大、自视甚高。
If you know someone like this, their narcissistic attitudes might irritate you.
如果你身边有这样的人，他们的自恋态度可能会让你感到厌烦。
But you might find it even more irritating to know that, according to new research, they are likely to be happier than other people.
但更让你抓狂的是，最新研究表明，这类人可能比其他人更快乐。
An ongoing study of narcissism by researchers at Queen's University Belfast has found such people might infuriate others but are less likely to be stressed or depressed.
贝尔法斯特女王大学的研究人员正在进行一项关于自恋的研究，他们发现这类人可能会激怒他人，但自身却更少感到压力或抑郁。
Writing about the research, the BBC’s Sean Coughlan says “They might have trampled over others and left a trail of emotional damage around them - but narcissists also seem to be insulated against feeling bad about themselves.”
英国广播公司的肖恩·考夫兰在报道这项研究时表示：“他们可能会践踏他人，留下一连串情感伤害——但自恋者似乎对自我否定具有免疫力。”
And their heightened sense of self-importance appears to give them "protective" qualities.
而他们认为自己是最重要的人这一感觉似乎赋予了他们一种“保护”特质。
Researchers have been trying to understand why narcissism appears to be more prevalent in areas such as politics, social media and celebrity culture and why narcissists' shameless, over-confident attitude seems to be rewarded rather than penalised.
研究人员一直试图弄明白，为什么自恋在政治、社交媒体和名人文化等领域更为普遍，为什么自恋者那种不知羞耻、过度自信的态度似乎会得到回报而非惩罚。
It does seem that they have the best of all worlds, which is not great news for shrinking violets.
他们似乎总能顺风顺水，这对那些胆小害羞的人来说可不是什么好消息。
And there’s more bad news for those who are shy and retiring: previous research by Queen’s University has also found that a ‘mental toughness’ helps narcissists succeed at work and in their social lives because they can overcome rejection and disappointment.
还有更糟糕的：贝尔法斯特女王大学之前的研究还发现，“心理韧性”帮助自恋者在工作和社交中取得成功，因为他们能克服拒绝和失望。
And other tests have found that narcissistic students do better in exams, not because they are more clever, but because of their confidence and assertiveness.
另外一些测试显示，自恋的学生考试成绩更好，并非因为他们更聪明，而是源于他们的自信和坚定。
But psychologist Dr Kostas Papageorgiou from the research team argues that these personality traits should not be seen as "either good or bad" but as "products of evolution" and "expressions of human nature".
但该研究团队的心理学家科斯塔斯·帕帕乔治乌博士认为，这些人格特质不应被简单定义为“好或坏”，而应被视为“进化的产物”和“人性的体现”。
So, at the end of the day, we are what we are, and that’s just something we can’t change.
所以，归根结底，我们就是我们自己，这是无法改变的事实。